eventfinda.co.nz 2018-12-19

# Privacy Policy - Eventfinda

We built Eventfinda to make it easy to share information with your friends and people around you. We understand you may not want to share personal details; that is why we give you control of your information. Please review this policy for information on how we collect, use, disclose and protect your personal information when you access and use our websites (www.eventfinda.co.nz, www.eventfinda.com.au and www.eventfinda.sg), apps or services, including Eventfinda embedded ticketing on third-party websites and social networks (together, the **Eventfinda Network** ).

We comply with applicable privacy and data protection laws (including the privacy and data protection laws of New Zealand, Australia and Singapore) when dealing with personal information. Personal information is information about an identifiable individual (a natural person). If you are based in the European Union and access and use the Eventfinda Network, the additional terms in the addendum to this privacy policy ( **GDPR Addendum** ) also apply to you.

In this policy, **Eventfinda** , **we** , **us** or **our** means the Eventfinda group of companies, comprising Eventfinda Limited and Eventfinda New Zealand Limited (both New Zealand companies), and Eventfinda Australia Pty Ltd (an Australian company).

This privacy policy does not cover personal information collected and held by persons outside New Zealand, Australia and Singapore who have licensed our technology. Our licensees are independent businesses and are subject to the applicable privacy and data protection laws in the jurisdictions in which they operate. We suggest that you review the privacy policy of the relevant licensee before you provide personal information to that licensee through its website or otherwise. Our licensees’ websites include http://www.wohintipp.at. This policy does not limit or exclude any of your rights under applicable laws.

This policy should be read in conjunction with our terms of service (accessible through the “Terms of Service” link at the bottom of each page of our websites) ( **Terms of Service** ).

By using or accessing any website, app or service in the Eventfinda Network, you are accepting the practices described in this privacy policy.

**Changes to this policy and our Terms of Service**

We may change this policy or our Terms of Service by uploading a revised policy or Terms of Service onto our website. The change will apply from the date that we upload the revised policy or Terms of Service. We encourage you to refer to this policy on an ongoing basis so that you understand our current privacy policy. Unless stated otherwise, our current privacy policy applies to all information that we have about you and your account.

**This policy was last updated on 25 May 2018.**

**The personal information we collect**

When you access or use the Eventfinda Network you provide us with two types of information: personal information you knowingly choose to disclose that is collected by us and usage information collected by us as you interact with our web site, app or service.

When you register with the Eventfinda Network, you are required to provide an email address, select a home region, and optionally choose a username. You may (if you choose) also provide us with other personal information, such as your name and other personal or preference information that you provide to us.

When you access or use the Eventfinda Network we collect your browser type and IP address. This information is gathered for all Eventfinda Network visitors. In addition, we store certain information from your browser using "cookies." A cookie is a piece of data stored on the user's computer tied to information about the user. We use session ID cookies to confirm that users are logged in. These cookies terminate once the user closes the browser. If you choose the “Remember me on this computer” option when logging in, we use a persistent cookie that stores your login to make it easier for you to login when you come back to the Eventfinda Network. You can remove or block this cookie using the settings in your browser if you want to disable this convenience feature.If you purchase tickets or merchandise through the Eventfinda Network, you are required to provide us with your name, email address, phone number, country and postcode (and postal address if purchasing physical tickets or merchandise). We use Payment Express and/or Braintree Payments to process the credit card transaction. We do not have access to your credit card information. You can view Payment Express’ privacy policy at <https://www.paymentexpress.com/privacy-policy>. You can view Braintree Payments’ privacy policy at <https://www.braintreepayments.com/legal/braintree-privacy-policy>.

If you post content that includes any personal information about anyone other than you, you must obtain all necessary consents from the relevant individual to enable us to collect, use, hold and process that information in accordance with our Terms of Service.

Any improper collection or misuse of information provided on the Eventfinda Network or posting of Content that breaches any third party right (including Intellectual Property Rights and privacy rights) is a violation of the Terms of Service and should be reported to support at eventfinda dot co dot nz.

If you choose to use our invitation service to tell a friend about our site, we will ask you for your friend's email address. We will automatically send your friend a one-time email inviting him or her to visit the site. Eventfinda Network web sites store this information to send this one-time email, to register a friend connection if your invitation is accepted, and to track the success of our referral program. If your friend does not accept your invitation within a reasonable period, we delete this information.

If you are an event promoter, venue or artist that chooses to list or promote events through the Eventfinda Network, we collect the personal information (if any) that you provide to us when you set up your event listing.

**Who do we collect your personal information from**

We collect personal information about you from:

  * you, when you provide that personal information to us, including via our websites, apps and services, through any registration or subscription process, through any contact with us (e.g. telephone call or email), or when you buy or use our services and products.
  * third parties where you have authorised this (e.g. when you use Facebook to login into your account) or the information is publicly available.

If possible (and with the exception of the invite a friend feature noted above and personal information include in Content uploaded by other users), we will collect personal information from you directly.

If you have a concern regarding personal information about you included in Content uploaded by other users, please contact us through the Help Centre.

**How we use your personal information**

We may use your personal information:

  * to provide our websites, app and services to you.
  * to send you newsletters that you choose (opt in) to receive. You can stop receiving our newsletters by following the unsubscribe instructions included in our emails or through your profile settings.
  * if you purchase tickets through the Eventfinda Network, to contact you about your tickets and/or the event if necessary.
  * to improve the Eventfinda Network.
  * to respond to communications from you, including enquiries and complaints.
  * to conduct research and statistical analysis (on an anonymised basis).
  * to tailor content or advertisements to you.
  * to protect and/or enforce our legal rights and interests, including defending any claim.
  * for any other purpose authorised by you or applicable law.
  * to respond to lawful requests by public authorities, including to meet law enforcement requirements.

We may occasionally use your email address to send you notifications regarding new services offered by the Eventfinda Network that we think you may find valuable.

If you use our premium advertising or ticketing services, we may use your personal information:

  * to undertake credit checks of you (if necessary).
  * to bill you and to collect money that you owe us.

We may transfer your information in the case of a sale, merger, consolidation, liquidation, reorganisation or acquisition.

**Disclosing your personal information**

Your email address is never displayed to anyone on the Eventfinda Network, unless you include it in Content you post.

Your email address may be displayed in emails if you use the Eventfinda Network to connect with other people, like when sending friend invites. Other personal details will only be displayed if you fill them in - the nature of social networking websites means your details will be visible to others - but only the details you choose to supply.

If you post Content on the Eventfinda Network, you do so at your own risk. Any personal information you post as part of Content will be accessible to other users. You should review your Content before posting it to ensure that you are not posting personal information you do not want to make public. Please be aware that no security measures are perfect or impenetrable. We cannot control the actions of other users with whom you may choose to share your pages and information. Therefore, we cannot and do not guarantee that Content you post on the Eventfinda Network will not be viewed by unauthorised persons. We are not responsible for circumvention of any privacy settings or security measures contained on the Eventfinda Network. You understand and acknowledge that, even after removal, copies of Content may remain viewable in cached and archived pages or if other users have copied or stored your Content.

We may disclose your personal information to:

  * another company within the Eventfinda group.
  * if you purchase merchandise or tickets to an event, the relevant event promoter, organiser or venue.
  * any business that supports the Eventfinda Network, including any person that hosts or maintains any underlying IT system or data centre that we use to provide the Eventfinda or that we use to process payments.
  * a credit reference agency for the purpose of credit checking you (where relevant).
  * other third parties (for anonymised statistical information).
  * a person who can require us to supply your personal information (e.g. a regulatory authority).
  * any other person authorised by applicable law (e.g. a law enforcement agency).
  * professional advisers e.g. accountants, lawyers, auditors.
  * any other company in the case of a sale, merger, consolidation, liquidation, reorganisation or acquisition.
  * any other person authorised by you.

Other companies within the Eventfinda group and businesses that support our services and products may be located within or outside New Zealand, Australia or Singapore. This may mean your personal information is held and processed outside your country of residence. Please see the GDPR Addendum for further information about personal data transfers from the European Economic Area.

**Links To Other Web Sites**

Eventfinda Network websites contain links to other websites. We are not responsible for the privacy practices of other web sites. We encourage our users to be aware when they leave our site to read the privacy statements of each and every web site that collects personal information. This privacy policy applies solely to information collected by Eventfinda Network websites, apps and services.

**Third Party Advertising**

Advertisements that appear on the Eventfinda Network are sometimes delivered (or "served") directly to users by third party advertisers. They automatically receive your IP address when this happens. These third party advertisers may also download cookies to your computer, or use other technologies such as JavaScript and "web beacons" (also known as "1x1 gifs") to measure the effectiveness of their ads and to personalize advertising content. Doing this allows the advertising network to recognize your computer each time they send you an advertisement in order to measure the effectiveness of their ads and to personalize advertising content. In this way, they may compile information about where individuals using your computer or browser saw their advertisements and determine which advertisements are clicked. Eventfinda does not have access to or control the cookies that may be placed by the third party advertisers. Third party advertisers have no access to your contact information stored on the Eventfinda Network unless you choose to share it with them.

This privacy policy covers the use of cookies by the Eventfinda Network and does not cover the use of cookies or other tracking technologies by any of its advertisers.

**Changing or Removing Information**

Access and control over personal information on the Eventfinda Network is readily available through the profile editing tools on all Eventfinda Network web sites, including eventfinda.co.nz. Eventfinda Network users may modify or delete any of their profile information at any time by logging into their account. Information will be updated immediately. Should you want your details removed completely from the Eventfinda Network there is a simple 'cancel my account' feature in your profile settings on any web site in the Eventfinda Network. You can cancel your Eventfinda Network account at any time. Cancelling your account will remove your personal details from the Eventfinda Network database. Removed information may persist in backup copies for a reasonable period of time but will not be available to members of the Eventfinda Network.

**Protecting your personal information**

We will take reasonable steps to keep your personal information safe from loss, unauthorised activity, or other misuse. We implement appropriate technical and organisational measures to ensure a level of security appropriate to risks inherent in processing personal information.

You can play an important role in keeping your personal information secure by maintaining the confidentiality of any password and accounts used in relation to our products and services. Please do not disclose your password to third parties. Please notify us immediately if there is any unauthorised use of your account or any other breach of security.

**Accessing and correcting your personal information**

Subject to certain grounds for refusal set out in applicable law, you have the right to access personal information that we hold and to request a correction to your personal information. Before you exercise this right, we will need evidence to confirm that you are the individual to whom the personal information relates. In respect of a request for correction, if we think the correction is reasonable and we are reasonably able to change the personal information, we will make the correction. If we do not make the correction, we will take reasonable steps to note on the personal information that you requested the correction.

You can access and correct much of the personal information we hold about you through your user profile.

If you want to exercise either of the above rights in relation to information we may hold about you that is not accessible through your user profile, or you do not wish to use your user profile to access or correct personal information we hold about you, please contact us through the Help Centre. Your email should provide evidence of who you are and set out the details of your request (e.g. the personal information, or the correction, that you are requesting).

**Internet use**

While we take reasonable steps to maintain secure internet connections, if you provide us with personal information over the internet, the provision of that information is at your own risk.

**Terms of Service and disputes**

Your use of the Eventfinda Network, and any disputes arising from it, is subject to this Privacy Policy as well as our Terms of Service and all of its dispute resolution provisions including arbitration, limitation on damages and choice of law.

If you have any questions about this privacy policy, please contact us through the Help Centre.

**GDPR addendum**

If you are based in the European Union ( **EU** ) and use the Eventfinda Network, these additional terms ( **GDPR Addendum** ) form part of our privacy policy.

The General Data Protection Regulation ( **GDPR** ) regulates the collection, processing and transfer of EU individuals’ personal data (as defined in the **GDPR** ). The personal information described in our privacy policy is personal data under the GDPR. We are committed to complying with the GDPR when dealing with personal data of our website visitors and service users based in the EU.

For the purposes of the GDPR, we are the data controller (as defined in the GDPR) when processing personal data collected by us when you access or use the Eventfinda Network.

This GDPR Addendum was drafted with brevity and clarity in mind. It does not provide exhaustive detail of all aspects of our collection and use of personal data. However, we are happy to provide any additional information or explanation needed. For further information, please contact us through the Help Centre.

**Processing personal data**

The personal data we may process consists of the personal information described in our privacy policy. This personal data may be processed for the purposes outlined in our privacy policy.

The legal basis for our processing of personal data is your consent or that processing is necessary for the performance of a contract to which you are a party or that processing is necessary for the purposes of our legitimate interests (except where such interests are overridden by your fundamental rights and freedoms which require protection of personal data).

Despite the above, we may process any of your personal data where such processing is necessary for compliance with applicable laws.

You do not have to provide us with a username or email address to browse our websites.

When you register with the Eventfinda Network, you are required to provide an email address, select a home region, and optionally choose a username. If you do not provide us with this personal data we will not be able to set up an account for you.

If you purchase tickets or merchandise through the Eventfinda Network, you are required to provide us with your name, email address, phone number, country and postcode (and postal address if purchasing physical tickets or merchandise), and you are also required to provide your credit card information (as noted in our privacy policy, credit card information is received by our credit card payments processors only, and we do not have access to this information). If you do not provide us with this personal data we will not be able to sell you a ticket or merchandise.

Where you use certain services available through the Eventfinda Network, we may ask for other personal information. Some of this information is mandatory and some is optional (this will be indicated on the relevant form). If you do not provide us with information that is mandatory for the relevant service, we will not be able to provide you with that service.

**Your rights**

Your rights in relation to your personal data under the GDPR include:

  * **right of access** \- if you ask us, we will confirm whether we are processing your personal data and provide you with a copy of that personal data.
  * **right to rectification** \- if the personal data we hold about you is inaccurate or incomplete, you have the right to have it rectified or completed. We will take every reasonable step to ensure personal data which is inaccurate is rectified. If we have shared your personal data with any third parties, we will tell them about the rectification where possible.
  * **right to erasure** \- we delete your personal data when it is no longer needed for the purposes for which you provided it. You may request that we delete your personal data and we will do so if deletion does not contravene any applicable laws. If we have shared your personal data with any third parties, we will take reasonable steps to inform those third parties to delete such personal data.
  * **right to withdraw consent** \- if the basis of our processing of your personal data is consent, you can withdraw that consent at any time.
  * **right to restrict processing** \- you may request that we restrict or block the processing of your personal data in certain circumstances. If we have shared your personal data with third parties, we will tell them about this request where possible.
  * **right to object to processing** \- you may request that we stop processing your personal data at any time and we will do so to the extent required by the GDPR.
  * **rights related to autonomous decision making, including profiling** – you have a right to not be subject to a decision based solely on automated processing including processing, which produces legal effects concerning you or similarly significantly affects you, except where such automated decision making is necessary for entering into, or the performance of, a contract with you, is authorised by applicable laws or is based on your explicit consent.
  * **right to data portability** \- you may obtain your personal data from us that you have consented to give us or that is necessary to perform a contract with you. We will provide this personal data in a commonly used, machine-readable and interoperable format to enable data portability to another data controller. Where technically feasible, and at your request, we will transmit your personal data directly to another data controller.
  * **the right to complain to a supervisory authority** \- you can report any concerns you have about our privacy practices to the relevant data protection supervisory authority.

Where personal data is processed for the purposes of direct marketing, you have the right to object to such processing, including profiling related to direct marketing.

If you would like to exercise any of your above rights, please contact us contact us through the Help Centre. If you are not satisfied by the way your query is dealt with by our data protection officer, you may refer your query to your local data protection supervisory authority e.g. in the United Kingdom, this is the Information Commissioner’s Office.

**Children**

We do not intend to collect personal data from children aged under 13. If you have reason to believe that a child under the age of 13 has provided personal data to us through our website and/or by using our services, contact us through the Help Centre.

**Cookies**

We use cookies (an alphanumeric identifier that we transfer to your computer’s hard drive so that we can recognise your browser) to monitor your use of the website. We use cookies (and other interactive techniques e.g. javascript and web beacons) as follows:

  * to remember users’ actions and preferences.
  * to identify the user, including allowing login functionality.
  * to analyse use of the website.
  * to measure the effectiveness of advertising.
  * to present advertising and Content relevant to users’ interests.

Some of these cookies (and other interactive techniques) are essential for enabling website functionality, e.g. session-based first party login cookies and permanent "remember me" cookies for automatic login. Others such as advertising (third party) and content related (first party) cookies aim to enhance the performance of the website and/or improve the user experience.

Consent to make use of these cookies can be withdrawn by contacting the Help Centre. Note that you will not be permitted to use the Eventfinda Network once consent has been withdrawn.

Information about Google’s cookies is available from: <https://www.google.com.au/policies/technologies/types/>. Google’s privacy policy relating to its cookies is available at <https://www.google.com/policies/privacy/partners/>. If you would like to customise or opt out of these settings please visit: <https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout>.

Google Adwords presents advertising relevant to your interests generated from data relating to your access and use of the website or our services. Google places cookies on your browser to collect information about your past use of the website and then places ads on sites across the internet that are more likely to be of interest to you. If you would like to customise or opt out of Google’s behavioural advertising, you can visit Google’s ads settings at <https://adssettings.google.com/>.

You can learn more about interest-based advertising and opt out of interest-based advertising from participating online advertising companies at the following links:

  * Network Advertising Initiative (NAI) – <http://optout.networkadvertising.org/>
  * Digital Advertising Alliance (DAA) – <http://optout.aboutads.info/>
  * Digital Advertising Alliance EU (EDAA) – <http://www.youronlinechoices.com/>
  * DAA AppChoices page – <http://www.aboutads.info/appchoices>

Please note that opting out of interest-based advertising does not mean you will no longer be served advertising. You will continue to receive generic ads.

You can control and/or delete cookies as you wish. You can delete all cookies that are already on your computer and you can set most browsers to prevent them from being placed. If you do this, however, you may have to manually adjust some preferences every time you visit our website and attempt use our services, you may not be able to access certain parts of our website or services, and some functionalities may not work. You can find out more information about how to change your browser cookie settings at <http://www.aboutcookies.org.uk/>.

**International transfer of data**

The personal data we collect through our website and/or the provision of services may be transferred to, and stored in, a country operating outside the European Economic Area ( **EEA** ). Under the GDPR, the transfer of personal data to a country outside the EEA may take place where the European Commission has decided that the country ensures an adequate level of protection. In the absence of an adequacy decision, we may transfer personal data provided appropriate safeguards are in place.

We may transfer EU individual’s personal data from the EU to Eventfinda companies in New Zealand, Australia or Singapore.  New Zealand is recognised by the European Commission as a country that ensures an adequate level of data protection and we rely on this decision in transferring personal data to New Zealand. Eventfinda Australia Pty Ltd (our Australian company) has entered into Standard Contractual Clauses as published by the European Commission.

Some of the personal data we collect is processed by third party data processors in other countries, including the United States and Australia. Where personal data is transferred outside the EEA or New Zealand, it will only be transferred to countries that have been identified as providing adequate protection for EEA data or to a third party where we have approved transfer mechanisms in place to protect your personal data (e.g. to organisations in the United States under the EU-U.S. Privacy Shield framework or by entering into the European Commission’s Standard Contractual Clauses). For further information, please contact us using the details set out in our privacy policy.

**Data retention policy**

Personal data that we collect and process will not be kept longer than necessary for the purposes for which it is collected, or for the duration required for compliance with applicable law, whichever is longer.

**Contacting us**

You can contact us through the Help Centre.

The name and contact details of our European representative are: James McGlinn, support at eventfinda dot co dot nz.
